<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lina&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://leenahere.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lina&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://leenahere.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bachelor Thesis</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/bachelorthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/bachelorthesis/</guid>
      <description>In 2016 and 2017 I wrote my thesis about conversational interfaces. My goal was to establish a design and development process for conversational interfaces. I mainly based my theories on Pangaro&amp;rsquo;s design for conversation, Grice&amp;rsquo;s cooperative principles and &amp;ldquo;The Media Equation&amp;rdquo; by Reeves and Nass.
To proof my theoretical concepts I programmed a facebook chatbot with wit.ai that was able to look up recipes. The bot was tested in a live trial and in a survey testers were able to judge the effectiveness of the conversation with the chatbot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTWK Smart Driving</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/smartdriving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/smartdriving/</guid>
      <description>In 2017 I was part of the team that participated in the Audi Autonomous Driving Cup. My main task was to implement Occupancy Grid Maps, which were used for object detection and parking.
The following year I took over team leadership and focused on the implementation of the World Service.
You can find more information about the HTWK Smart Driving Team here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper – SKILL 2018</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/paperschoolrobots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/paperschoolrobots/</guid>
      <description>As part of the advanced seminar I attended in my second master semester, I wrote a paper with three fellow students about the utilization of robots in german highschools. The paper was accepted for publication at the student conference for computer science. The full text can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Girls Arduino Workshop</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/codegirlsarduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/codegirlsarduino/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS / macOS Software Developer</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/ulyssesapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/ulyssesapp/</guid>
      <description>In 2014, I began working in customer support at Ulysses. I helped customers deal with the macOS and iOS app, recorded feature requests and reported bugs. When I came back to Leipzig after my internship in 2016, I switched roles and started co-developing the app. I implemented new features like reading time goals and fixed bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internship</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/lufthansa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/lufthansa/</guid>
      <description>I completed my mandatory internship at Lufthansa in the &amp;ldquo;Sales &amp;amp; Digital Customer Experience&amp;rdquo; department. I supported several IT project managers in projects related to the Lufthansa website and mobile platforms. I also supported a project in which a facebook chatbot was developed as an MVP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT Heater</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/mcaheater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/mcaheater/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website for dghd2019</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/dghd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/dghd/</guid>
      <description>In 2018 and 2019 I completely rebuilt the website for the conference for the german didactics of higher education which took place at the university of Leipzig in March 2019. The website can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic Algorithms – Art Gallery Problem</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/geneticalgorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/geneticalgorithm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof – Ackermann is not primitive recursive</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/pvs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/pvs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/nasahackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/nasahackathon/</guid>
      <description>In 2016 I participated in the NASA International Space Apps Challenge in Leipzig. In a team of three we programmed an Android app to predict delays of flights to and from the airport Leipzig/Halle (LEJ). The repository can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning with Lego Mindstorms EV3</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/blog/ml-with-ev3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/blog/ml-with-ev3/</guid>
      <description>Today I present to you: Another Machine Learning tutorial that no one asked for.
As part of my master thesis, I developed a workflow and exercises to bring Machine Learning (ML) to LEGO Mindstorms EV3. To give you a bit of background about my thesis, my aim is to create an educational programming environment to teach high school students about Machine Learning algorithms using LEGO Mindstorms. Finding a suitable task for teaching kids (or rather teenagers) ML algorithms wasn’t the easiest considering the limited resources and sensors the EV3 has to offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing the Math</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/blog/doing-the-math/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/blog/doing-the-math/</guid>
      <description>My main task the past two weeks was to figure out the learning objectives for a Machine Learning course. This is not an easy task considering that most courses you find online are designed for adults, more specifically adults with a background in computer science or another STEM field. Therefore, my work this week focused on the following three subtasks:
 Examine different ML online courses and summarize the main learning objectives Look into teaching contents of german math classes (grade 8 to 12) Merge these outcomes to compose the learning objectives for my course  One and Two were quite straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Proposal</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/blog/research-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/blog/research-proposal/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Kelly Sikkema on Unsplash
Initially, I was asked to write the related work abstract for my thesis this week to summarize all the relevant papers and other sources I&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled upon so far. While googling (yes, I google a lot these days) how to best write related work abstracts, I figured why not do some general research on master thesis requirements (yes, I should&amp;rsquo;ve probably googled that a while ago).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/blog/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/blog/research/</guid>
      <description>Photo by James Pond on Unsplash
This week I started my research for my masters thesis. To say &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m struggling&amp;rdquo; would be an understatement. The research part of any thesis is probably the most crucial part of the whole odyssey. It&amp;rsquo;s the part that sets the tone for the next 6 months. I guess struggling with the research will mean less struggle with the rest of the process. Hopefully…right?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>