<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social on Lina Peters</title>
    <link>https://leenahere.github.io/tags/social/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social on Lina Peters</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://leenahere.github.io/tags/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Girls Arduino Workshop</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/codegirlsarduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/codegirlsarduino/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor @ Jugend hackt</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/jugendhacktmentor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/jugendhacktmentor/</guid>
      <description>Jugend hackt, which is a hackathon for kids and teenagers, takes place in cities all over Germany. At the hackathon children and teenagers (12-18 years old) come together for a weekend and work on various projects in groups. The event is all about improving the world with code and the kids can be creative and pursue their individual goals while learning about different technologies. In August 2018 the hackathon took place in Halle and I mentored a group of the younger kids who programmed a website to provide information about chicken farming in Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor @ helpING Academy</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/helpingmentor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/helpingmentor/</guid>
      <description>The helpING! academy for high school girls interested in STEM is a free, innovative, one-week academy for career and study choice orientation within the framework of the project &amp;ldquo;helpING - meet tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s social challenges with STEM competence and social commitment&amp;rdquo; funded by the Federal Ministry of Education and Research (BMBF). The project helpING! is supported by the Federal Ministry of Education and Research in the funding line &amp;ldquo;Success with STEM - New Opportunities for Women&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/nasahackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leenahere.github.io/projects/nasahackathon/</guid>
      <description>In 2016 I participated in the NASA International Space Apps Challenge in Leipzig. In a team of three we programmed an Android app to predict delays of flights to and from the airport Leipzig/Halle (LEJ). The repository can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>